
[
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "During the First World War, which country signed the Peace Treaty (1917) with Germany?",
    "correct_answer": "Russia",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "England",
      "USA",
      "Austria"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "When did United Kingdom declared war on Germany which lead to World War II?",
    "correct_answer": "3rd September 1939",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "4th April 1939",
      "18th August 1939",
      "28th August 1939"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "When was ancient Rome founded?",
    "correct_answer": "753 BC",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "776 BC",
      "752 BC",
      "742 BC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "When was NATO signed?",
    "correct_answer": "1949",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1990",
      "1948",
      "1950"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "In which year, Alexander the Great become the king of Macedonia?",
    "correct_answer": "336 BC",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "323 BC",
      "350 BC",
      "200 BC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which Mountain’s volcano buried Pompeii city with ash in 79 AD?",
    "correct_answer": "Mount Vesuvius",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Mount Pelee",
      "Mount Tambora",
      "Mount Etna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Queen Elizabeth I of England belongs to which dynasty?",
    "correct_answer": "Tudor",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Stuart",
      "York",
      "Normandy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which one was the capital city of Byzantine Empire?",
    "correct_answer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Venice",
      "Rome",
      "Vienna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Who was the King of Britain during the First World War ?",
    "correct_answer": "George V",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Philip I",
      "Anarew VIII",
      "Jonn Vll"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Who was popularly known as Africa’s Gandhi?",
    "correct_answer": "Nelson Mandela",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Mir Karzai",
      "Firoz Gandhi",
      "M.K.Gandhi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "In 1804 Napoleon I crowned himself as Emperor of France.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Who united Norway, Denmark and, Sweden?",
    "correct_answer": "Margaret I of Denmark",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Albert King of Sweden",
      "Eric of Pomerania",
      "Haakon VI of Norway"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The policy of racial discrimination followed in South Africa was called?",
    "correct_answer": "Apartheid",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Non-Aligned",
      "Civil Rights Movement",
      "Suffrage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Marco Polo was a traveller from Spain.",
    "correct_answer": "False",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "True"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The Second World War started in the year 1942.",
    "correct_answer": "False",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "True"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The tomb of Tutankhamun was discovered by Howard Carter and George Herbert.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which two countries were involved in a Hundred Years War?",
    "correct_answer": "England and France",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Turkey and Austria",
      "Palestine and Israel",
      "Germany and Russia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "In which European country feudalism process was first started?",
    "correct_answer": "French",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Italy",
      "England",
      "Russia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "In year 1789 George Washington became the first president of USA.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Countries",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Aztec civilization was originated in which country?",
    "correct_answer": "Mexico",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "USA",
      "Greece",
      "Egypt"
    ]
  }
]
